<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Continuum Mechanics Review - misc</title><link href="https://saiwal.github.io/continuum_mechanics_review/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://saiwal.github.io/continuum_mechanics_review/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://saiwal.github.io/continuum_mechanics_review/</id><updated>2020-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>About this blog</title><link href="https://saiwal.github.io/continuum_mechanics_review/about-this-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Admin</name></author><id>tag:saiwal.github.io,2020-09-15:/continuum_mechanics_review/about-this-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome dear reader. This is a shared blog made for informal discussions about current research happening in the field of continuum mechanics. While publishing journals papers is an effective way to communicate latest reseach to the public there is a need to have an informal forum here people can voice …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome dear reader. This is a shared blog made for informal discussions about current research happening in the field of continuum mechanics. While publishing journals papers is an effective way to communicate latest reseach to the public there is a need to have an informal forum here people can voice their opinions, findings, interests with the community. This is meant to be a fun participatory activity among us enthusiasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to join&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website along with the source is available for everyone on the github &lt;a href="https://github.com/saiwal/continuum_mechanics_review"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;. Go ahead and clone the repo. Some familiarity with &lt;a href="https://docs.getpelican.com/en/stable/"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt; is desirable to fully understand how it works. Pelican is a python based static website generator. Only the owner of the repo can update the website. However anyone from public can send a pull request with their contribution. Therefore, good knowledge of working
with the commandline and git is essential. This also helps a researcher working inthis field since a lot of collaboration and coding is often required. If someone wishes to brush up their skills there are some good tutorials available on youtube. Some links would be recommended in the references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About the repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two branches, master and gh-pages. 'master' branch contains the source files of the blog, i.e. the content, config files, and the generated output. Once generated the website is uploaded to the 'gh-pages' branch. Only master branch need to be cloned to contribute. If you wish to test the website, create a local branch for testing purposes so that no pull requests are sent for files other than those in 'content'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What should I write about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to voice your opinion, ideas or call for collaborations via this platform. There are no strict rules other than good etiquettes. Plagiarism should be avoided, if you wish to share someone elses work make sure to cite them in your article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will be updated periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pelican tutorials:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.getpelican.com/en/stable/"&gt;https://docs.getpelican.com/en/stable/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown cheatsheet:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.github.com/pdfs/markdown-cheatsheet-online.pdf"&gt;https://guides.github.com/pdfs/markdown-cheatsheet-online.pdf&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with git tutorials: &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learngitbranching.js.org/"&gt;https://learngitbranching.js.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RGOj5yH7evk"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RGOj5yH7evk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with Commandline(Linux):&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=px8D72loRVg&amp;amp;list=PLSmXPSsgkZLuJKJhvL1U384aHesbVDekO"&gt;The Linux Command Line Ultimate Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>